PAUL ENWEREM

<u>paulthechampion28@gmail.com</u> <u>www.paulthechampion.com</u> www.linkedin.com/in/paul-enwerem-9a307518b/ (416) 896-3327

Objective

An ambitious, young, and charismatic Software developer with over 5+ years of professional experience in MongoDB, Express JS, React JS, Redux JS, Node JS (M, E, R, R, N) and many more, seeking full-time employment as a mid-senior level Software developer.

Skills

PROGRAMMING AND DEVELOPMENT LANGUAGES, TOOLS, SKILLS, AND SOFTWARE

♣ Html 5 and CSS 3	♣ JavaScript	↓ JQuery
♣ Node JS	React JS	↓ MongoDB
	♣ Redux	👃 Vue JS
♣ REST API	↓ C#	🖶 GIT
Agile Framework (JIRA)	♣ GitHub	📥 Amazon Web Service (AWS)
↓ Unit Test (JEST)	Bitbucket	Bug Fixing and Problem Solving

Experiences

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER
S&P GLOBAL
LONDON, ONTARIO
OCTOBER 2021 – DATE

- Working with one of the biggest financial service companies in the NYSE
- Writing code in Vue JS, Node JS, ASP.NET and C# with a Jest unit test coverage of 90%+
- Worked with WCAG 2.0 standards to make the clients web application more accessible to people with disabilities.
- Building new features like Stock, ETF and MF Charts, Funds Compare tools, calendars, calculators etc.
- ₩ Worked with a team of 15 and properly utilized the Agile framework.
- Regular production support to investigate and fix Live bugs on the clients' production environment.

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER DAVITO IMMIGRATION SERVICE BRAMPTON, ONTARIO MAY 2020 – OCTOBER 2021

Despite the hardships of the pandemic and there being a shortage of opportunity, I was able to persevere and land an opportunity in a new country. Davito Immigration service is an immigration company based in Brampton, Ontario. My team was tasked with creating and deploying their online web application. I completed this task by using the following:

- ♣ Node JS and Express to handle the backend and Api Creation
- React JS to handle the front end.
- Followed the Figma design patterns to ensure my code is in line with the Company's requirements.
- Css and JavaScript for styling
- ♣ Git for Version control, Heroku and Go daddy for deployment, using DNS target to combine both.
- Registering for SSL certificate to keep the site safe and secure.

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER NADA CREATE

REMOTE

NOVEMBER 2019 – MAY 2020

- Wrote well-designed, testable, efficient code using Node JS, React JS, Express for the company's e-commerce web application.
- Application of Passport JS to create and authenticate Users for the e-commerce application.
- Worked with Paystack API to integrate payments for each product.
- ♣ Meticulously adhered to the Figma UI/UX design to ensure compliance with client's requirements.
- ♣ Always delivered my code on time and completed all the companies Acceptance criteria always.

WEB DEVELOPER

KEER NG

LAGOS, NIGERIA

DECEMBER 2018 - MARCH 2019

- ♣ Developed and designed the front-end of a web application to showcase products and services for Keer NG
- → Delivered responsive, cross-browser compatible and accessible website.
- Wrote code mainly in HTML, CSS, and vanilla JavaScript.
- ♣ Produced stunning visual elements of web applications by translation UI/UX design wireframes into code
- ₩ Worked directly with client to develop technical solutions for business cases.

Education

BABCOCK UNIVERSITY, OGUN STATE, NIGERIA B.SC INTERNATIONAL LAW AND DIPLOMACY

- 2015 2019
 - Active member of the Babcock University Computer Club (B.U.C.C).
 - Honors degree (3.75 G.P.A.)
 - Led a class of over 150 students as an Assistant Class Representative.

NEW HORIZON CODING BOOT CAMP, OGUN STATE, NIGERIA APRIL 2018- AUGUST 2018

♣ Primary Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, C#.

CALEB INTERNATIONAL SECONDARY SCHOOL LAGOS, NIGERIA

2009-2015